Hossein Mirjalali



mirjalali.hosein@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/hossein-mirjalali



https://www.glipsite.com/me

Summary

Software engineer who has been working in web industry for 3 years, using Django as my tool of choice. I have prior experience with PHP, and Java.

I built my personal project (glipsite.com) with Django from scratch, designing my own library that interacts with Twitch API, for retrieving data, authenticating users, etc.

Experience



Founder and Developer

Glipsite

Jun 2021 - Present (7 months +)

A hub where you can watch your favorite Twitch streamers' top clips, and get updated on all the fuss. Started as a simple project for my own usage, I realized this website can be useful for others in the Twitch community.

The project was setup with Django Cookiecutter (cookiecutter/cookiecutter-django), with a couple of tweaks. I utilized the django allauth package that's included in cookiecutter to quickly sign up my users with their existing Twitch account with OAuth, eliminating the need to store their password on my server.

The clips are fetched via the public Twitch API, using Celery. I then use the django's awesome template engine to sort the data and showcase relevant clips, using Twitch's embedded clips feature, so I don't have to store any video clips either, which really helps since as of now, there is more than 5 million clips data stored on the PostgreSQL database.

The project is run on a 2 GB RAM, 2-core Ubuntu server using Docker. There are multiple Docker images that are managed and spun up by docker-compose.

Users can request to watch a specific broadcaster's clips, in which case, I will use their OAuth token to make a request to Twitch API, and fetch that broadcaster's data.

I learned a lot about Django with this project, I fell in love with FBV's and Celery, and learned how to use them to my advantage.



Back End Developer

Freelance

Sep 2018 - Jun 2021 (2 years 10 months)

Used Django Python to prototype some start-up ideas, and study the way Django works under the hood.



Web Developer

RAL Offshore

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018 (6 months)

Rich web app for internal communication, such as invoices, supply requests to off-shore cargo ships, etc.

Built with PHP (codeigniter), this web app helped with the process of paperwork, and the way they are handled. The goal was to build a lightweight internal app that is only accessible to the company, and the main focus was the communication between the cargo ships that are off the shore, and the company main HQ, in Tehran. This communication mostly consisted of placing invoices for the needed parts, food, and tools for the cargo to be delivered to them on their next docking, or an emergency delivery. This app removed a lot of overhead in the process, cutting the required paperwork by 50%.

Education



The Iranians University

Master's degree, Computer Science 2021 - 2023



M Kharazmi University

Bachelor's degree, English Language and Literature, General 2015 - 2020

Licenses & Certifications



Introduction to Programming Using Python - Tehran Institute of Technology (MFT)

Skills

Django REST Framework • Web Design • REST API • Python (Programming Language) • Django • Linux • Docker • Git • Celery • Django